A Guide to the Office of the President, Special Records, ca. 1955-1977
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
University of Virginia Office of the President Special Records ca. 1955-1977
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/3.791
This collection consists of 6,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access is prohibited for ten years from the date of creation unless special permission is granted by the President's Office. Under the terms of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Sec. 2.1-343 (4)), the records of the President or other chief executive officer of any state-supported institution of higher education are exempt from the law's access provisions. Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection is an archival transfer to the library by the Office of the President, Pavilion VIII University of Virginia on 1981 February 23.
Scope and Content Information
Special record files of the President, University of Virginia, including material regarding athletics, faculty, finals, Easters, Founder's Day, Gay Student Union, University Senate, the undergraduate readers library, Afro-American Affairs and search committees.
Contents List
- Ad Hoc Committee Files
  - Ad Hoc Committee Files: I.D. Cards 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee Files: Proposal to National Endowment for Humanities (1972-1973) 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee Files: Search for Black Faculty (1971-1972-1973-1974) 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee Files: Search for New Dean of Admissions 6/12/75 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee Files: Search for Secretary of the General Faculty 1976-1977 (Box 1)
- Special Committee Files
  - Boxing 1973-1974 (Box 1)
  - Club Sports 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Dining Hall Building 1971-1973 (Box 1)
  - Law-Graduate Business Housing 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - Medical Policy Hospital 1972-1974 (Box 1)
  - Outpatient Dept. & Clinical Servic Building 1972-1973 (Box 1)
  - Personnel Advisory 1968-1972 (Box 1)
  - Steering Committee on University Planning 1971-1972 (Box 1)
  - Survey and Maitenance - Formal Gardens 1976 (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate Library 1972-1976, 2 folders (Box 1)
- General Files
  - Afro-American Affairs Office 1976 (Box 2)
  - Athletic Department 1966-1971, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Berkeley, Francis L. 1972-1976 (Box 3)
  - Business and Finance-Shea, Vincent 1969, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Carr's Hill Entertainment Fund 1975 (Box 3)
  - Charlottesville, Albemarle, University Relations 1971-1975 (Box 3)
  - Commonwealth Day 1970-1973, folders 1, 2, 3, 4 of 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Commonwealth Day 1973, folder 5 of 5 folders (Box 4)
  - Condolences 1970-1975 (Box 4)
  - Crawford, Edwin-Files 1972-1974 (Box 4)
  - Crawford, Edwin-Files re University Athletic Events 1971-1974 (Box 4)
  - Equal Opportunity Program - Saunier, Paul 1978 July (Box 4)
  - Faculty-General-Minutes of Meetings 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Faculty-New, as of September, 1974 1974 (Box 5)
  - Faculty-University of Virginia 1974 Sept. (Box 5)
  - Finals Week 1974, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Finals Week-School of Law 1974 (Box 5)
  - Finals Week-Summer Session 1974 (Box 5)
  - Founder's Day, 1974 1971-1974, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Gay Student Union 1976, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Invitations to Home Football Games 1973 (Box 6)
  - Invitations/Acceptances/Regrets to Home Basketball Games 1972-1973 (Box 7)
  - Invitations/Acceptances/Regrets to Home Basketball Games 1973-1974 (Box 7)
  - Lambeth House 1975 (Box 7)
  - Law School-Low, Peter 1969 (Box 7)
  - Letters to General Assembly-re Undergraduate Library 1976 (Box 7)
  - Minority Students/Black Faculty and Administration 1975 Oct. (Box 7)
  - Patents (Permanent) 1955-1973 (Box 7)
  - President's Discretionary Fund 1976 March 9 (Box 7)
  - Report of Easter's Weekend Commission 1975 October 1, folder 1 of 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Report of Easter's Weekend Commission 1975 October 1, folder 2, 3, 4 of 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Student Affairs - Easter's Commission 1975-1977 (Box 8)
  - University Development Steering Committee 1973-1974 (Box 8)
  - University Senate 1974-1975 (Box 8)